

Curriculum Vitae

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Scotto Elena



- Via Ceriolo, 39, Sant'Albano Stura, 12040, Cuneo, Italy
- **=** +39 3337470010
- elena.scotto@outlook.it
- Skype live: elena.scotto

Sex F | Date of birth 06 /07/1995 | Nationality Italian

OUTLOOK

The impact Science and Mathematics have on real life drove me the decision to expand my knowledge on these subjects. During my academic career I focused on math courses and on the application of mathematics using different programming languages.

The completion of my studies summed up in design and development of a Linear Programming algorithm to find the optimal value which its performance is been analysed testing on real life problems.

The teaching activities and the Erasmus study experience in Germany further enhanced my teamwork abilities and problem-solving skills.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

09/2017 - expected 21/10/2019

Master degree in Mathematics

University of Turin, Department of Mathematics "G. Peano"

- Advanced mathematics
- Computational algorithms, models and software in the LP and physics fields Thesis: "A Long Path-Following Step Algorithm"

09/2014 - 12/2017

Bachelor degree in Mathematics

University of Turin, Department of Mathematics "G. Peano"

- Algebra, mathematical analysis, geometry, mathematical physics, numerical analysis and computer science
- Mathematical statistics and Operations Research
- Hand on work in ICT and computational mathematics

09/2009 - 06/2014

High school with course of studies in sociology and psychology

Liceo Scientifico Statale "G. Ancina" of Fossano.

Basic grounding in social and human sciences.

WORK EXPERIENCE

09/2018 - 09/2019

Italian teacher

Fachsprachenzentrum der LUH, Hannover, Germany.

- Planning lessons and exercises
- Cooperation with colleagues
- Performance lessons in classroom

06/2014 - 06/2017

Waitress

Tavola del Chiostro – Casa Regina Montis Regalis, Vicoforte, Italy.

- Taking customer orders and delivering food and beverages
- Cooperate and communicate with all serving and kitchen staff

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

Italian

Other language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
B2	B2	B2	B2	B2
Language Certificate CLA				
B1	B1	B1	B1	B1
FSZ Certificate				

German

English

Levels: A1/A2: Basic user - B1/B2: Independent user - C1/C2 Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Communication skills

- Good multilingual communication skills gained through my Erasmus experience in Hannover

Organisational / managerial skills

- Competence of creating and keeping deadlines developed in the University career
- Detail oriented with creative problem-solving attitude
- Ability to work under pressure and in team in a dynamic environment.

Digital skills

- Basic programming knowledge in Python, Matlab, R, C, C++, SAS
- Git and SourceTree
- Implementation of LP algorithms to solve complex problems

Driving licence

В

Referring to the European Commission laws (D.lgs. Privacy n. 196/03), my personal data can be inserted in data banks for personal recruitment or used for specific communications related to recruitment.

Sant'Albano Stura, October 2nd, 2019

Elena Scotto